<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andreas Filser</title>
    <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andreas Filser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://afilser.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Statistik 1 &amp; 2 an der Uni Oldenburg</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/courses/uni-oldenburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/courses/uni-oldenburg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata-Kurse am BIBB</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/courses/bibb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/courses/bibb/</guid>
      <description> Kursunterlagen     Einführung in Stata mit statistischem Hintergrundwissen     Einführung in Stata für fortgeschrittene Anwender:innen anderer Programme     Tabellenexport in Word und Latex mit Stata     Programmieren mit Stata     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites     Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A first post</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/spoonful-series/01-spoonful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/spoonful-series/01-spoonful/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/blog\spoonful-series\01-spoonful.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: blog  My layout is: single-series   does this work?     or this?      Let&amp;rsquo;s start.
beginning     middle     end     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile      https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile      https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README     This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
 https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata at BIBB</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/bibb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/bibb/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;#34;postcards&amp;#34;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;#34;postcards&amp;#34;) [1] ‘0.2.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A second post</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/spoonful-series/02-spoonful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/spoonful-series/02-spoonful/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/blog\spoonful-series\02-spoonful\index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: blog  My layout is: single-series  Images in this page bundle: /blog/spoonful-series/02-spoonful/sidebar-inverse.jpg   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;#34;blogdoown&amp;#34;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;#34;blogdown&amp;#34;) [1] ‘1.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A third post</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/spoonful-series/03-spoonful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/spoonful-series/03-spoonful/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/blog\spoonful-series\03-spoonful\index.markdown  Here is my R Markdown source file: blog\spoonful-series\03-spoonful\index.Rmarkdown You&#39;ll want to edit this file, then re-knit to see the changes take effect in your site preview.
 To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: blog  My layout is: single-series  Images in this page bundle: /blog/spoonful-series/03-spoonful/featured-photo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;)  Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection\day02\03-blogdown\index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection  My layout is: single-series   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication list</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication_list/</guid>
      <description>Click here for a detailed publication list including abstracts
<<<<<<< HEAD
Filser, Andreas, P. Willführ, Kai (2022). Sex Ratios and Union Formation in the Historical Population of the St. Lawrence Valley. PLOS ONE, (17)6, e0268039.Müller, Dana, Filser, Andreas, Frodermann, Corinna (2022). Update: Identifying Mothers in Administrative Data. FDZ-Methodenreport, (NA)2022-01, NA.Filser, Andreas, Stadtmüller, Sven, Lipp, Robert, Preetz, Richard (2022). Adolescent School Injuries and Classroom Sex Compositions in German Secondary Schools.</description>
=======
Filser, Andreas, Achard, Pascal, Frodermann, Corinna, Müller, Dana, Wagner, Sander (2023). Mothers’ Employment in a High- and Low- Maternal Employment Regime – a Comparison between France and Germany [working Paper]. SocArXiv, 1–29.Zimmermann, Florian, Filser, Andreas, Haas, Georg-Christoph, Bähr, Sebastian (2023). The IAB-SMART-Mobility Module: An Innovative Research Dataset with Mobility Indicators Based on Raw Geodata.</description>
>>>>>>> newmain
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex Ratios and Union Formation in the Historical Population of the St. Lawrence Valley</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2022_sex_ratios_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2022_sex_ratios_and/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   The ratio of men and women in the adult population, i.e. sex ratio, has long been recognized as a key demographic constraint for partnering behavior. However, the literature remains contradictory on how sex ratio imbalances influence partnering behavior, suggesting either higher or lower rates of male marriage being associated with male-skewed sex ratios. These contradictory findings are likely due to data limitations. Cross-sectional data or limited observation periods preclude studies from distinguishing sex ratio effects on timing from effects on the overall likelihood of marriage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adolescent School Injuries and Classroom Sex Compositions in German Secondary Schools</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2022_adolescent_school_injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2022_adolescent_school_injuries/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   School injuries are an important adolescent health problem. Previous research suggests that relevant risk behaviors for school injuries, risk-taking and aggression, are highly susceptible to peer effects. Specifically, evidence suggests that the ratio of men and women in peer groups (sex ratio) affects individuals&amp;rsquo; propensity for aggression and risk-taking. However, potential associations of classroom sex ratios with adolescent school injury risks have not been studied so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Identifying Mothers in Administrative Data</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2022_update_identifying_mothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2022_update_identifying_mothers/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Administrative data of the Federal Employment Agency provide an important data base for labour market research. However, the Federal Employment Agency&amp;rsquo;s tasks define what kind of information is recorded. Therefore, some information is missing that is relevant for various research purposes. One example is information on childbirth, which can be important when analysing female employment biographies. It is still mainly mothers who interrupt their employment to care for their children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bleibt Alles Anders?! Zur Akzeptanz Hybrider Lehr- Und Lernformate Während Der COVID-19-Pandemie</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2021_bleibt_alles_anders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2021_bleibt_alles_anders/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Unser Beitrag geht der Frage nach, welche langfristigen Effekte und Möglichkeiten zur Verzahnung von Präsenz- und Online-Lehre im Regelbetrieb entstehen können. Mithilfe der Annahmen des Tech- nology Acceptance Model (TAM) untersuchen wir Faktoren, die auf die Akzeptanz und zukünftige Nutzungsintention hybrider Lehr- und Lernformate wirken. Die Ergebnisse (N=666) zeigen, dass rund 34 % der Studierenden hybrides Lernen akzeptieren und zukünftig nutzen wollen. Multivariate Re- gressionsanalysen belegen die Wichtigkeit der wahrgenommenen Nützlichkeit und Nutzerfreundlich- keit von digitalen Lehr- und Lernformaten sowie die Verfügbarkeit notwendiger technischer Ressour- cen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal Changes in Life Satisfaction and Mental Health in Emerging Adulthood During the COVID-19 Pandemic. Risk and Protective Factors</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2021_longitudinal_changes_in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2021_longitudinal_changes_in/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   The COVID-19 pandemic has disrupted emerging adults&amp;rsquo; daily routines due to social distancing, stay-at-home orders, and public and educational facilities&amp;rsquo; closure. This article uses longitudinal panel data from Germany (N = 625) to explore how the COVID-19 pandemic affects emerging adults&amp;rsquo; mental health and life satisfaction. Specifically, we investigate risk and protective factors for within-person changes in life satisfaction and mental health using change score models. Our analysis reveals three main findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Local Sex Ratios Approximate Subjective Partner Markets? Evidence from the German Family Panel</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2021_do_local_sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2021_do_local_sex/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Sex ratios have widely been recognized as an important link between demographic contexts and behavior because changes in the ratio shift sex-specific bargaining power in the partner market. Implicitly, the literature considers individual partner market experiences to be a function of local sex ratios. However, empirical evidence on the correspondence between subjective partner availability and local sex ratios is lacking so far. In this paper, we analyzed how closely a set of different local sex ratio measures correlates with subjective partner market experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Skewed Sex Ratios Associated with Violent Crime? A Longitudinal Analysis Using Swedish Register Data</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2021_are_skewed_sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2021_are_skewed_sex/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   There is widespread concern in both the popular and academic literature that a surplus of men in a population intensifies mating competition between men, particularly unpartnered men, resulting in increased violence towards both men and women. Recent contributions challenge this perspective and argue that male mating competition and levels of violence will be higher when sex ratios are female-skewed. Existing empirical evidence remains inconclusive. We argue that this empirical ambiguity results from analyses of aggregate-level data, which put inferences at risk of ecological fallacies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up your social</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/social/</guid>
      <description>There are five places where you can choose to show social icons. Here is the tl;dr:
 site header (set in config.toml), site footer (set in config.toml),  homepage (set in content/_index.md),  about page in the sidebar (set in content/about/sidebar/index.md), and  contact page (set in content/form/contact.md).  Read on to learn how to set up your social icons, and how to show/hide them.
Configure social     Wherever you end up wanting to show your social icons, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to start by setting up the links in your site config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style your site colors</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/color-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/color-themes/</guid>
      <description>You can totally customize your site&amp;rsquo;s theme colors within minutes of creating a new site. Read on to find out how, and decide which of the three options meets your needs.
Use a color theme     Hugo Apéro includes 8 built-in color themes that work &amp;ldquo;out of the box.&amp;rdquo; This means you can use a color theme to quickly customize the look of your site without needing to write any CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style your site typography</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/fonts/</guid>
      <description>As with color themes, you can completely customize your site&amp;rsquo;s fonts within minutes of creating a new site. How you do it depends on how much control and customization you need.
Embedded fonts     Hugo Apéro includes 6 embedded fonts that work &amp;ldquo;out of the box.&amp;rdquo; We selected 3 serif and 3 sans-serif options that we thought looked good with this theme, in our humble opinions. All embedded fonts include real italics so you may emphasize to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content ❤️!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An evergreen post</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/evergreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/evergreen/</guid>
      <description>Rendering mathematical equations     Examples from the mathjax demo. But they work with katex as well.
Rmarkdown     In .Rmarkdown documents, you can use either
$a \ne 0$ to get inline math: \(a \ne 0\). There is no conflict with using dollar symbols regularly, because knitr automatically escapes freestanding dollar symbols.
And you can use
$x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a}.$$ to get a math paragraph:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A campfire</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/talk/campfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/talk/campfire/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to give this talk! Stay tuned for video and slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using panelsets</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/seedling/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of panelset.js by Garrick Aden-Buie, from his xaringanExtra package: https://pkg.garrickadenbuie.com/xaringanExtra/#/panelset
For example, this panelset:
Hello! 👋 hello
 Goodbye 💨 goodbye
  Was created by combining this theme&amp;rsquo;s panelset and panel shortcodes:
{{&amp;lt; panelset class=&amp;#34;greetings&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Hello! :wave:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}}  hello {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Goodbye :dash:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}}  goodbye {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; /panelset &amp;gt;}} You could also revert to HTML as well. For example, this panelset:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/talk/second-seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/talk/second-seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Rmarkdown post</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description> Air quality     with(airquality, boxplot(Temp ~ Month)) with(airquality, plot(Ozone ~ Temp)) mlev &amp;lt;- levels(with(airquality, as.factor(Month))) with(airquality, plot(Ozone ~ Temp,  pch = as.numeric(mlev),  col = mlev)) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/talk/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/talk/seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Outcomes And Sex Ratio</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2019_social_outcomes_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2019_social_outcomes_and/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   (Abstract not available)
 Back to publication list</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex Ratio and Men&#39;s Long-Term Mating</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2019_sex_ratio_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2019_sex_ratio_and/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   (Abstract not available)
 Back to publication list</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tachyons for Style</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/project/giraffes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/project/giraffes/</guid>
      <description>Tachyons is a design system that allows you to design gorgeous interfaces in the browser with little effort.      Because Speed     Building this static site generator theme was the first time I used an Atomic (or Functional) CSS system like Tachyons. It&amp;rsquo;s a design system that provides very small (which means fast) CSS modules that you can use in your HTML. So, rather than writing every line of CSS, you apply the style you need as you write your HTML with easy to understand shorthand class names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Grid Scaffold</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/css-grid-scaffold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/css-grid-scaffold/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.”     — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
 Overview     Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palmer Penguins</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/project/penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/project/penguins/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.”     — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
 Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bakeoff</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/project/bakeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/project/bakeoff/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website.      Functional Form     This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Contact Form</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/built-in-contact-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/blog/built-in-contact-form/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website.      Functional Form     This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mehr Männer, Mehr Gewalt? Eine Präzisierung Möglicher Kausalmechanismen</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2018_mehr_maenner_mehr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2018_mehr_maenner_mehr/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Eine unausgewogene Geschlechterzusammensetzung - also ein Überschuss von Personen männlichen bzw. weiblichen Geschlechts - in einer Bevölkerung kann durch Geschlechterdifferenzierung der Fertilitäts-, Mortalitäts- und Migrationsvorgänge entstehen. Die familiensoziologische, demografische und evolutionsbiologische Forschung hat zahlreiche Indizien für verschiedene gesellschaftliche Konsequenzen einer unausgewogenen Geschlechterzusammensetzung zusammengetragen. Besondere Aufmerksamkeit gilt dabei dem Thema Aggression und Gewalt, allerdings mit diametralen Vorhersagen: manche Beiträge konstatieren einen positiven, andere einen negativen Zusammenhang. Die empirische Evidenz beruht bisher vornehmlich auf historischen Indizien sowie gemischten Forschungsergebnissen in kontemporären Gesellschaften.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krankenkassen im regionalen Vergleich</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2017_krankenkassen_im_regionalen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2017_krankenkassen_im_regionalen/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   (Abstract not available)
 Back to publication list</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographische Maskulinisierung und Gewalt</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/dem-masku/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/dem-masku/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Vor dem Hintergrund des demographischen Ungleichgewichts von Männern und Frauen in Asien beschäftigen sich diverse Autoren mit möglichen Konsequenzen eines Frauen- oder Männermangels, unter anderem auf die Gewaltinzidenz in den betroffenen Gesellschaften oder Regionen. Allerdings präsentieren sich die bisherigen theoretischen Ansätze wie auch die empirische Evidenz als uneinheitlich. Der Beitrag gibt einen Überblick über sozialwissenschaftliche und evolutionstheoretische Perspektiven auf die Fragestellung und versucht, diese zu integrieren. Darüber hinaus werden empirische Befunde dargestellt und eingeordnet sowie eigene Projekte vorgestellt und Forschungsdesiderata formuliert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Sincere thanks to Alison Hill for creating this Hugo Apéro theme and to Silvia Canelón and Shazia Ruybal-Pesántez for providing their code for repo-diving 🤿.
In this spirit, you can find the code for this page here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
