<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>France on Andreas Filser</title>
    <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/tags/france/</link>
    <description>Recent content in France on Andreas Filser</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://afilser.netlify.app/tags/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mothers’ Employment in a High- and Low- Maternal Employment Regime – a Comparison between France and Germany [*working Paper*]</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2023_mothers_employment_in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2023_mothers_employment_in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;France and Germany, the two biggest EU economies with relatively similar welfare states differ profoundly in how childbirth affects the careers of mothers. Building on newly harmonized administrative data we document differences in mothers’ employment trajectories, show how these differences evolved between 1997-2019, and analyse whether the influence of individual and firm-level characteristics on maternal employment are similarly structured in two countries with such different post-maternal employment regimes. Our results show that previously employed mothers in Germany reducing their employment by over 2.3 years more than their French counterparts in the six years including and following birth. Part-time work increases by over 40% among those continuing to work in Germany and by about 25% in France. We document a common trend towards increased post-maternal employment and increased part-time work in later cohorts in both countries. Individual- and firm-level factors have a much more stratified effect on post-maternal employment in France, with low-income and low-education mothers faring comparatively worse. While mothers’ employment is reduced to a much greater extent in Germany, the high maternal employment French model seems to particularly disfavour the return of mothers with low human capital into the labour market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sex Ratios and Union Formation in the Historical Population of the St. Lawrence Valley</title>
      <link>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2022_sex_ratios_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://afilser.netlify.app/publication/2022_sex_ratios_and/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;#abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ratio of men and women in the adult population, i.e. sex ratio, has long been recognized as a key demographic constraint for partnering behavior. However, the literature remains contradictory on how sex ratio imbalances influence partnering behavior, suggesting either higher or lower rates of male marriage being associated with male-skewed sex ratios. These contradictory findings are likely due to data limitations. Cross-sectional data or limited observation periods preclude studies from distinguishing sex ratio effects on timing from effects on the overall likelihood of marriage. In this paper, we use historical family reconstitution data to study the association of sex ratios with marriage patterns in the French colony of the St. Lawrence Valley in North America (1680-1750). The population experienced a substantial male-skew from sex-selective immigration during the early period of the colony. The long-running observation period allow for differentiating the timing and overall likelihood of marriage. Finally, the data enable us to study the effects of male-skews on the population-level as well as the regional and parish level. Cox proportional hazard models reveal that while male-skewed sex ratios are associated earlier marriage for women, the association with men&amp;rsquo;s marital biographies is less clear-cut. We find that men marry later when sex ratios are more male-skewed, yet we do not find a substantial reduction in the overall likelihood of marriage for men. Our findings reveal that male-skewed sex ratios do not necessarily result in an increase of never married men. We discuss the implications of our findings for the sex ratio literature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
