<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Andreas Filser</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Andreas Filser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sex Ratios and Union Formation in the Historical Population of the St. Lawrence Valley</title>
      <link>/publication/2022_sex_ratios_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2022_sex_ratios_and/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   The ratio of men and women in the adult population, i.e. sex ratio, has long been recognized as a key demographic constraint for partnering behavior. However, the literature remains contradictory on how sex ratio imbalances influence partnering behavior, suggesting either higher or lower rates of male marriage being associated with male-skewed sex ratios. These contradictory findings are likely due to data limitations. Cross-sectional data or limited observation periods preclude studies from distinguishing sex ratio effects on timing from effects on the overall likelihood of marriage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adolescent School Injuries and Classroom Sex Compositions in German Secondary Schools</title>
      <link>/publication/2022_adolescent_school_injuries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2022_adolescent_school_injuries/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   School injuries are an important adolescent health problem. Previous research suggests that relevant risk behaviors for school injuries, risk-taking and aggression, are highly susceptible to peer effects. Specifically, evidence suggests that the ratio of men and women in peer groups (sex ratio) affects individuals&amp;rsquo; propensity for aggression and risk-taking. However, potential associations of classroom sex ratios with adolescent school injury risks have not been studied so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Identifying Mothers in Administrative Data</title>
      <link>/publication/2022_update_identifying_mothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2022_update_identifying_mothers/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Administrative data of the Federal Employment Agency provide an important data base for labour market research. However, the Federal Employment Agency&amp;rsquo;s tasks define what kind of information is recorded. Therefore, some information is missing that is relevant for various research purposes. One example is information on childbirth, which can be important when analysing female employment biographies. It is still mainly mothers who interrupt their employment to care for their children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bleibt Alles Anders?! Zur Akzeptanz Hybrider Lehr- Und Lernformate Während Der COVID-19-Pandemie</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_bleibt_alles_anders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_bleibt_alles_anders/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Unser Beitrag geht der Frage nach, welche langfristigen Effekte und Möglichkeiten zur Verzahnung von Präsenz- und Online-Lehre im Regelbetrieb entstehen können. Mithilfe der Annahmen des Tech- nology Acceptance Model (TAM) untersuchen wir Faktoren, die auf die Akzeptanz und zukünftige Nutzungsintention hybrider Lehr- und Lernformate wirken. Die Ergebnisse (N=666) zeigen, dass rund 34 % der Studierenden hybrides Lernen akzeptieren und zukünftig nutzen wollen. Multivariate Re- gressionsanalysen belegen die Wichtigkeit der wahrgenommenen Nützlichkeit und Nutzerfreundlich- keit von digitalen Lehr- und Lernformaten sowie die Verfügbarkeit notwendiger technischer Ressour- cen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longitudinal Changes in Life Satisfaction and Mental Health in Emerging Adulthood During the COVID-19 Pandemic. Risk and Protective Factors</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_longitudinal_changes_in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_longitudinal_changes_in/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   The COVID-19 pandemic has disrupted emerging adults&amp;rsquo; daily routines due to social distancing, stay-at-home orders, and public and educational facilities&amp;rsquo; closure. This article uses longitudinal panel data from Germany (N = 625) to explore how the COVID-19 pandemic affects emerging adults&amp;rsquo; mental health and life satisfaction. Specifically, we investigate risk and protective factors for within-person changes in life satisfaction and mental health using change score models. Our analysis reveals three main findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Local Sex Ratios Approximate Subjective Partner Markets? Evidence from the German Family Panel</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_do_local_sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_do_local_sex/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Sex ratios have widely been recognized as an important link between demographic contexts and behavior because changes in the ratio shift sex-specific bargaining power in the partner market. Implicitly, the literature considers individual partner market experiences to be a function of local sex ratios. However, empirical evidence on the correspondence between subjective partner availability and local sex ratios is lacking so far. In this paper, we analyzed how closely a set of different local sex ratio measures correlates with subjective partner market experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Skewed Sex Ratios Associated with Violent Crime? A Longitudinal Analysis Using Swedish Register Data</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_are_skewed_sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_are_skewed_sex/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   There is widespread concern in both the popular and academic literature that a surplus of men in a population intensifies mating competition between men, particularly unpartnered men, resulting in increased violence towards both men and women. Recent contributions challenge this perspective and argue that male mating competition and levels of violence will be higher when sex ratios are female-skewed. Existing empirical evidence remains inconclusive. We argue that this empirical ambiguity results from analyses of aggregate-level data, which put inferences at risk of ecological fallacies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Outcomes And Sex Ratio</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_social_outcomes_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_social_outcomes_and/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   (Abstract not available)
 Back to publication list</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex Ratio and Men&#39;s Long-Term Mating</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_sex_ratio_and/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_sex_ratio_and/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   (Abstract not available)
 Back to publication list</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mehr Männer, Mehr Gewalt? Eine Präzisierung Möglicher Kausalmechanismen</title>
      <link>/publication/2018_mehr_maenner_mehr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018_mehr_maenner_mehr/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Eine unausgewogene Geschlechterzusammensetzung - also ein Überschuss von Personen männlichen bzw. weiblichen Geschlechts - in einer Bevölkerung kann durch Geschlechterdifferenzierung der Fertilitäts-, Mortalitäts- und Migrationsvorgänge entstehen. Die familiensoziologische, demografische und evolutionsbiologische Forschung hat zahlreiche Indizien für verschiedene gesellschaftliche Konsequenzen einer unausgewogenen Geschlechterzusammensetzung zusammengetragen. Besondere Aufmerksamkeit gilt dabei dem Thema Aggression und Gewalt, allerdings mit diametralen Vorhersagen: manche Beiträge konstatieren einen positiven, andere einen negativen Zusammenhang. Die empirische Evidenz beruht bisher vornehmlich auf historischen Indizien sowie gemischten Forschungsergebnissen in kontemporären Gesellschaften.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krankenkassen im regionalen Vergleich</title>
      <link>/publication/2017_krankenkassen_im_regionalen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2017_krankenkassen_im_regionalen/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   (Abstract not available)
 Back to publication list</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographische Maskulinisierung und Gewalt</title>
      <link>/publication/dem-masku/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/dem-masku/</guid>
      <description>Abstract   Vor dem Hintergrund des demographischen Ungleichgewichts von Männern und Frauen in Asien beschäftigen sich diverse Autoren mit möglichen Konsequenzen eines Frauen- oder Männermangels, unter anderem auf die Gewaltinzidenz in den betroffenen Gesellschaften oder Regionen. Allerdings präsentieren sich die bisherigen theoretischen Ansätze wie auch die empirische Evidenz als uneinheitlich. Der Beitrag gibt einen Überblick über sozialwissenschaftliche und evolutionstheoretische Perspektiven auf die Fragestellung und versucht, diese zu integrieren. Darüber hinaus werden empirische Befunde dargestellt und eingeordnet sowie eigene Projekte vorgestellt und Forschungsdesiderata formuliert.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
